Decisions, decisions, decisions.
Life is full of decisions.
What are you going to study?
What job are you going to take?
Who are you going to marry?
What car are you going to buy?
Are you going to get the A vegetables or the chocolate?
Yeah, decision decisions and decisions are really important when it comes to coding as well, because
that is how so many things operate.
Is this bigger than that?
Is that the same as that?
And we need to have decisions.
In fact, a whole area of what is called flowcharts is often used in trying to define and decide and
make clear how your program's logic works.
So does the lamp work?
No.
Well, is it plugged in?
Then plug it in.
Yes, it is plugged in.
And so we have flowcharts to try and work out decisions.
Now obviously it can get more and more complex these flowcharts as more and more decisions have to be
made.
And so in this section we want to have a look at a special command, which is the if statement and related
parts to it.
The if else statement that help you work your way through decisions and help you make decisions in Python.
So now our programs are going to start to move up to the next level and get quite exciting, because
this is where we start to see how we can use the power of everything.
We've been doing all the statements, all the variables, all the operators, and bring them to the
next level by using decisions.
So let's head on over to Python and see what we can do with decisions.